♪ Music ♪
Good evening to all the listeners of J-WAVE WOW MUSIC.
I am Seisaku, bass vocalist of Mongol800.
This program is presented by one creator every month.
navigates the show as a monthly presenter.
Every week, we introduce music that we think is amazing,
with the creator of the music.
and the creator of the music in a late-night music roundtable discussion.
July's monthly presenter is
Seisaku, who sings and plays bass for Mongol800, will be our presenter for the month of July.
Today, we welcome Kenta from Wanima as our guest,
We would like to bring you a late-night music discussion.
Last May, when Kenta-kun from Wanima was presenting
I was a guest on the show.
This time, I will be the monthly presenter.
I will be in charge of the program as a monthly presenter.
I think it is inevitable to invite Kenta-kun.
I have started this program on WOW MUSIC.
Monpachi and Wanima's split EP "Aiya Aiya
I hope we can dig deeper into that work as well,
I would like to talk about behind-the-scenes stories and many other things.
I look forward to hearing from you.
Hmmm...
Mm-hmm.
mmm
Hm.
J-WAVE WOW MUSIC Today we welcome Wanima's bass vocalist Kenta-kun.
Please do.
On the 22nd of the previous month, we released a split EP, Aiaia.
We have released it.
It started with J-WAVE.
Yes, it did.
You have been promoting it recently as well.
Yes, we have. TV and so on.
Thanks to that, Monpachi has been very busy.
That's right.
You have been busy, which is rare in recent years.
Yes, it has.
Here, again, let me dig deeper into Kenta's musical lutes.
Thank you very much.
How and why did you get started in music? Do you have one?
Yes, there is. When I was in my third or second year of junior high school, I was asked to play in a band at a school festival.
At that time, I also had a guitar instructor at Wanima.
I've been with my instructor since I was 2 or 3 years old.
I said, "Let's do something cool at the festival with him.
I went out, but I got a big reception at the festival for my bad performance.
I went down on stage and cried a lot. I was so frustrated.
I was frustrated and didn't want to give up.
I want to show them how cool I am, and I want to show them how much better I can be, so I have been doing this for a long time.
You suddenly became a bass vocalist?
At that time, it was just the four of us.
We wanted to get out of the small town of Amakusa in Kumamoto Prefecture.
It was also in the name of the band. We called ourselves Freedom.
The name of the band was Freedom.
We were a four-piece band, and the bass player left.
I had to do the bass vocals, so I only did the vocals.
That's how I became the bass vocalist.
I see.
When did you start writing songs?
When I was in high school, I didn't have anything else to do but play in a band.
After high school, I only played in bands.
We entered contests and so on.
We were talking about who was going to write the music.
I said, "Let's write a song tomorrow.
So, with the drummer who was with us at the time, we wrote a song until tomorrow.
We wrote a song until tomorrow.
The three members who were the best were to write the lyrics.
So, Gyoshin came up with a batch of songs.
He asked me to let him listen to it, and I played acoustic guitar while he got used to it.
He sang about how he doesn't cry when he gets into a fight.
This one didn't make me cry.
The drummer sang a little.
The drummer sang the next fist fist fist fist fist fist.
Then, "dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun dun.
I thought, "I have no choice but to do this.
I started to write the lyrics.
Is this the first CD you bought, or is it a song that you have a special attachment to?
The CD "Message" by Mongol 800 is one of the most memorable songs I ever bought.
When I didn't know Seisaku-san and Sashi-san's faces anymore.
I was a student.
I had 3 or 4 CDs at home at that time.
CDs of messages.
There were so many CDs that my grandma had to take them to her farm,
I had so many CDs that my grandma used to hang Message CDs in the field to keep the crows away,
There were so many CDs.
There are so many CDs, so you can use them.
Grandma, no, no, just the ones with messages.
I guess the songs that mean a lot to me are..,
Rainbow by Mongol 800.
Why Rainbow?
When the music video for Rainbow came out, the three of us were in the studio together, and we had probably 15 hours of studio time reserved.
We went into the studio with no idea what we were going to do, and we just yelled, "I'm going to do something," and said, "Ah!
I think it was around 8:00 or 7:00 p.m. when the M V came out, and we were in the second half of the 15 hours.
I immediately contacted Kyosaku-san, and he told me that this was the place to be, and that he had taught me the really important core of music.
I could feel the warmth in the simplicity of the music.
I didn't want to add guitars, or various sounds, or anything else that would sound weird,
I was just at the point in my life when that song reached me, and I was trying to add guitars, various sounds, and other strange hozaiku-like things.
I immediately thanked Kyosaku-san for the great song.I immediately thanked Kyosaku for the great music.
He sent me an email right away.
I contacted him.
When I made the Pretty Good album, I wanted to make an album like my first album,
So, I was very particular about keeping the songs short, under 3 minutes.
I was a bit obsessive about keeping the songs short, under 3 minutes, and as I was working on the album, I felt that the songs were too rushed, and although they were nice to listen to, there was one song that was a bit too mid-tempo.
I had a demo of a mid-tempo song I was making on the ukulele, and I remember I just started playing it all up at once.
I thought that the approach had changed from the early days of Wanima, including the songwriting, but there was a song that I wanted to listen to a little bit, and in my mind, it was that lindow.
There's a piano.
There's a piano in there. String site.
You have strings and stuff in there, and the atmosphere changes first of all.
I thought it was nice to use a piano instead of bass, guitar, and drums, but after listening to the song, I thought that it conveyed what I wanted to convey and the atmosphere of the song,
I thought it was nice that when the chorus comes in, it goes back to "Wanima. I thought, "That's great.
I thought it was nice that when you get to the chorus, you go right back to "wanima." I thought it was a natural incorporation of the song, or the breadth of the song, or what I wanted to do, and this approach, this song "Gentian" really changed the atmosphere.
Why was the timing right?
It was right around the time of the Kumamoto earthquake. It was also for Kumamoto,
Gentian is the flower of Kumamoto prefecture, and as the word "gentian" in the language of flowers says, gentians used to bloom in the mountains.
Gentians do not bloom in clusters. They bloom in their own places, but from our point of view, flowers growing around us were like grasses,
Even plants are individual works of art, so I wanted to clearly convey the idea that people should be able to realize their dreams and have hopes in their own places. I had a clear idea of what I wanted to convey in the melody and the lyrics,
I made a lot of mistakes, and there were many things I was still inexperienced in, such as the key, tempo, etc. I tried many different approaches, and finally settled on that one.
I was experimenting with different approaches, and finally settled on that feeling of starting with the piano.
Yes, I wanted to include the piano, including the possibility of the three of us playing together.
At that time, the scale of the concert was expanding to include domes, arenas, etc., and I wanted to broaden the scope of the concert and convey what I wanted to say more widely.
The piano piece by Lindow and the one where I thought, "Wow, backward, I can play the acoustic guitar" were from that day and that place.
I didn't have much of an image of Gojin's acoustic guitar, so I thought he must have played it a lot, and then I looked and listened again.
The same is true for the guitarist, thanks to the support of Monpachi, for example, we were able to perform at Rock in Japan together, which helped to broaden his range as a guitarist.
We started to have solo guitar parts in our live performances, and from that day and place, it became clear that we could finally produce the sound that we wanted to produce.
From here, I would like to talk more about the split EP "AIAIA". Thank you very much.
Yes, please.
The collaboration was already started with J-WAVE, wasn't it?
Yes, it was. It's been about a year or so.
We collaborated with J-WAVE in May last year, and on June 22nd, the day of the release, we were already back in Japan for promotion.
Yes, it's been about a year since we started working together on 5 songs while both of us are on tour.
Also, this year is the 50th anniversary of the reversion of Okinawa to Japan, and I really feel that this AIA EP is a piece of fate that I will remember for a long time to come.
It's true. The flow of the EP is so beautiful that we are surprised, but we started working on it in May last year as a guest, and I think in November.
We also had them appear at the Monpachi event.
I was at the event.
We had a light discussion about the schedule among the staff members.
It seemed that they were exploring the issue under the surface.
At the end of the year, I looked back at my e-mail and found that I contacted him on the 4th or 5th of December, and we went out for dinner on the 7th.
We went to eat sushi near here.
I wondered what Kenta was thinking and what he wanted to do.
Before we went out for dinner, I think we were catching up with each other and the staff to see how we could make 5 songs like this.
I thought it would be a waste to add more new songs, because they would be too scattered.
So, we decided to limit the number of songs we would write together to one, and we would cover each other's songs.
And let's cover each other's songs.
So, one song at a time.
Let's offer each other's songs.
So, I think there were a total of five songs as a starting point.
Yes, we did.
The reason we didn't convey our thoughts properly is because of how the five songs would flow together.
That's right.
I don't remember the taste of the sushi, but I wanted to convey my feelings without leaving them behind.
At that time, I wanted to ask you about the songs that you provided.
We did.
I asked, "Since we are here, what kind of music do you want? I asked him what kind of music he wanted to hear.
I said, "Well, it's not too late to start.
Yes, that's right. I made sure to leave nothing out. I did.
I would like to sing a song with Okinawan keywords or words related to Okinawa.
Flowers, place names, and so on.
I see... I see... I see... I see... I see... I see..,
I was thinking, "Well, we have not included the word "Okinawa" or keywords related to Okinawa in our songs, even in Monpachi. I remember bringing them back to Monpachi.
I remember bringing that back to Monpachi.
I had a hard time from there.
I had received such clear requests from Renta that if I gave him something completely different, he would be very disappointed.
It was pretty last minute to get the demo for the project.
Yes, yes, yes.
At that time, the idea of a cover was kind of vague, wasn't it?
Yes, we were. We told each other that we could do anything on Monpachi's songs.
I was trying to think of what we could cover.
At that time, I had a vague idea of what I wanted to do with 1106.
That's how it all started. We had to decide what kind of earliest we were going to collaborate on.
After some back and forth, Kenta contacted me.
At first, we were talking about me writing the A melody and Kyosaku doing the B melody.
But in Sucia, we stopped there.
It stopped there. Then, if you want, you can send me the A melody and Kyosaku-san the B melody via voice memo.
Let's do it.
The day after I returned home, I started to write the song, and I thought, "If it were Kyosaku-san, he would sing it like this.
If it were Sashi, he would sing like this, and if it were Sashi, he would play like this.
And since all five of us grew up on an island, I wanted to bring out the groove of the island where we grew up.
Then, one song was already done. I was afraid that Kyosaku would be angry with me.
But once my feelings overflowed, I finished all the songs. I gave it to him and told him to listen to it.
We were so lucky to be able to do that. It was like, "Kenta, I made everything.
When I heard it, I could already see many pictures, and when it was finished, I thought, "That's great.
The five of us gathered in a studio in Tokyo. At that time, we were already comparing our answers.
Kyosaku sang like this. Kyosaku sang like this, Kyosaku played like this. Sashi-san sang this way, and Sashi-san played this drum.
But that way of making music is quite rare, and it was a good time. We were making it up as we went along.
Kenta made the general framework, but we all went into the studio to finalize it,
The drums are the drums, and we work on them as we go along,
It's a good day, and it's filled with initial impulses, or rather, it's filled with the best of the best.
Split album EP Aiya
The lead single is going to be Aiya.
There are songs that we both contributed songs to each other.
The first one is Tingara, which we got from Wanima.
We won't give that song back to you.
When we finished it, we didn't want to give it to them if we could have.
I was sure Kenta was serious about this one.
We made it so well that even we could release a CD and put it out.
But when Tingara came back to me...
I thought, "Pachiyabe, you two are really serious.
I was like, "You two are serious.It was like, "You two are serious.
We've got the song and the mash ready to go.
The tingara at Wanima is complete.
We took that and
I took that, and from there, I thought of various arrangements based on what I wanted to make Kenta happy.
I've been thinking about how to make it simple in the style of Wanima, and I've come up with a lot of new ideas.
I thought about the range of expression that Monpachi can do now.
It's the first time for me to put steel pan in a song...
When I heard that song, I heard the sound of steelpan.
I heard the steelpan when I listened to that song, and I thought I'd like to add a little color to the time of day with the saxophone.
I was just trying to give it a little bit of color.
And then we started to arrange it.
I had a very good idea of what I wanted to do.
The part where Sasshi is playing the drums...
Seisaku's voice sings the part where Sasshi is playing the guitar.
I want him to sing a sweet and sour love song, a love song.
When I remember them, I still feel a pain in my heart.
I'd like to hear Mr. Seisaku's voice and Mr. Sasshi's drumming to express that kind of feeling.
It's kind of interesting, isn't it?
I heard that when I came out this morning.
It made my heart ache a little.
Mr. Seisaku and Mr. Sasshi, you've got to be serious!
Such seriousness!
And the Monpachi side offered to Wanima
Last Paradise.
The word "Last Paradise" itself
It is a bit of a big word, but it is equal to Okinawa.
It's a bit of a big word, but it's also a word that refers to a lot of things, like the times.
In the midst of all this tossing and turning, people are looking for healing.
Okinawa is a place where people come to seek healing
It's really a kind of paradise.
It's like there's something there, but it's not there.
There is a sense of emptiness.
It's like everyone is heading there.
That's why the lyrics of the songs that Kenta writes are so detailed and clear.
Kenta's lyrics are very detailed and clear.
On the other hand, Monpachi's music
On the other hand, the lyrics that Monpachi writes are simple words that can be understood in various ways.
It's a simple word, but it can be heard loudly.
But they can also be heard loudly or felt loudly.
I try to use words that can be heard and felt as loudly as possible.
That's what I did this time.
But there is one word that I've always wanted to use.
There is a word that I've always wanted to use.
Actually, it's the word "gotu".
Getto is a plant that is very familiar to Okinawans
It's a plant that's very familiar to Okinawans.
I heard a story about it.
For example, during the war, when the moonlight was shining on the beach
the moonlight reflecting off the beach, right?
Like a white thing.
The ghetto flower is white.
It's white and pink.
You can see the road while shining on it.
When I heard something like that...
I was vaguely interested in making a song with the keyword "ghetto" in it someday.
I had a vague idea that I wanted to write a song with the keyword "gotu" in it.
I had it in the back of a drawer somewhere.
I had been keeping it in the back of a drawer somewhere for a long time, and when Kenta asked for requests
I raised a drawer full of them.
He said he had a lot of ghettoes.
I wanted to put them in.
This is what I want Okinawa to be like now.
I want Okinawa to be like this.
This is what happens when you go to nature
Well, you know...
I was thinking that there is a flow of nature.
It's a vague song
but it's like I entrusted it to you.
Thank you very much.
It's a song.
But at a live performance.
The meaning of the song can be taken in a broad sense, but the arrangement of the music
But the arrangement of the song is quite refreshing.
It's exhilarating.
It's almost like the demo we received.
I didn't want to lose that feeling.
It starts out as a song.
It's like the wind of Urizm flowing in the air.
I had the image of singing with everyone at a stadium at the dawn of Corona.
It's a little bit light.
The guitar is played on a Gretsch.
I played it without distorting it too much.
I also sing lightly
I'm singing lightly and playing the drums lightly.
It's like I'm smiling.
I really didn't want to mess up the demo.
I didn't want to ruin the demo.
I made it again with the Wanima sound.
So you're comfortable with that too?
That's why Wanima and Monpachu
I think Wanima and Monpatu have similar melodies and beats.
I think they must be similar.
The winds of Urizum.
It's like the early summer breeze that blows in May and June.
And it's going to be released in June.
I hope it will be a good wind in many ways then.
I remember now.
You remember now?
The wind of URHYTHM
Ghetto Sound UrizmGet Sound U Rhythm
Based on the feelings and the process of making it like that.
I think it would be interesting to listen to it again
I think it will be interesting.
We are also planning to go on a live tour together. The contents have not been decided yet.
But I think you can look forward to it.
I don't think it would be interesting to just play against each other,
I think it would be good to add at least one more cover song.
I think there is no limit to what we can do because we are two bands that are pretty good at what we do.
We haven't even started yet, but I'm sure we can do it many times.
I hope we can multiply each other's performances.
So you will be performing live and also playing at the Wanima festival?
That's right. While also performing at the Onechan festival.
Our first festival.
Our first festival. It's going to be held at a place called Country Park in Kumamoto Prefecture, and it's the first time.
We wanted to hold the festival in Kumamoto Prefecture, reading the people who have helped us and reading the artists we love.
In my hometown.
I want to hold it in my hometown.
I am looking forward to it. What are you going to do next year?
I wanted to talk about that today.
For example, I was thinking that it would be great if we could go on an Asian tour together, such as Shanghai or Taiwan.
When we released the music video for "AIAIA", we received comments from people overseas in the comments section.
I tried to translate them, but I thought they were bad words and I didn't know what to do.
But they were really complimentary, and I think it would be great if we could tour Asia.
That's interesting.
We have been to Asia quite a few times, and we have been invited to festivals. Well, it's interesting.
Interesting?
If the food is okay, the Asian tour will be a success.
Success.
We went to a festival in Beijing once, I think. When we went to a festival in Beijing, or somewhere in Beijing.
Two days in a row, the only place open was a hotpot restaurant, and we had no choice but hotpot.
We like to eat good food, but there are people who don't like spicy food.
So if the food is good, we will succeed.
You need an event that takes you to a place with good food.
Yes, that's right. Let's go there. Do your research. Do your research now.
Music is fine. If you want.
Let's do a live broadcast.
That's right. From there, we'll do the Asian tour while recording.
Then we can come back and play the live takes on Wow!
I think if we show that we can make it happen, other artists will want to have a talk with us here.
It's great. This was really a good opportunity for us, and we have to be realistic.
We have come back in less than a year with a piece of work.
Next, we will tour Asia and come back here one more time.
Then we can talk about our new outlook.
We will no longer make our own original works.
I think we should ask Kenta to write all of ONPACHI's songs.
Next, I would like to ask you to write a little bit of Tingara's vocabulary.
Maybe he's already bald.
I'm afraid it's going to be a problem for both of us in our day jobs.
We may not even be able to look each other in the eye.
I'm really looking forward to it. For now.
I have nothing but images to look forward to.
I hope I can convey that to people who are listening to me and at the live concert on the same day.
I hope I can convey a lot of things to the people who are listening to us.
We are looking forward to having the most fun, so please continue to support us.
Please come and see the five of us.
Seisaku, who sings and plays bass for MONGOL800, has navigated the way.
How was WOW MUSIC?
It was a very rewarding time for me personally, including the critical production stories.
I would like to welcome iUNITY of BISH as our next guest.
It will be the first time for me to talk to him directly,
I would like to invite Mr. iUNITY of BISH to the event Monster BISH hosted by BISH.
I, Mr. Seisaku, have been on stage with him as a solo performer at the Monster BISH event.
I would like to have a music discussion based on that. Thank you very much for your cooperation.
See you again next week at this time.
Our partner so far has been Mongol800 Seisaku.
Please subscribe to our channel.